The Whale is a drama film directed by Darren Aronofsky.
A reclusive English teacher suffering from severe obesity attempts to reconnect with
his estranged teenage daughter for one last chance at redemption.
Charlie, played by Brendan Fraser.
Ellie, played by Sadie Sink.
Thomas, played by Ty Simpkins.
Liz, played by Hong Chau.
Mary, played by Samantha Morton.
Dan the Pizza Man, played by Sathya Sridharan.
The Whale is a 2022 American psychological drama film directed
by Darren Aronofsky and written by Samuel D.
Hunter, based on his 2012 play.
The film stars Brendan Fraser, Sadie Sink, Hong
Chau, Ty Simpkins, and Samantha Morton.
The plot follows a morbidly obese, reclusive English teacher who tries to restore his
relationship with his teenage daughter, whom he had abandoned eight years earlier.
The film was shot from March 8 to April 7, 2021, in Newburgh, New York.
The Whale premiered at the 79th Venice International Film Festival on
September 4, 2022 and received a polarized response.
Although critics lauded the acting, particularly Fraser, Chau and Sink, the
film's portrayal of obesity-related struggles drew criticism.
Notwithstanding, it was received with acclaim in the awards season.
At the 95th Academy Awards ceremony, The Whale won the Oscars for Best Actor (Fraser), Best
Makeup and Hairstyling and a Best Supporting Actress nomination for Chau.
At the 76th British Academy Film Awards, the film was nominated for Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Make Up & Hair, Best Supporting Actress (Chau) and Best
Actor for Fraser's performance, who also received a nomination for Best Actor in a Motion Picture – Drama at the 80th Golden Globe Awards.
It had a limited theatrical release in the U.S.
on December 9, before a wide release on December 21 by A24,
grossing $57.6 million against a budget of $3 million.
The film explores themes of depression, nurse, missionary, idaho, bible.
The tone is emotional.